## Abdel-Khafid SALAOU

## **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

khadaf3@amail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Wellfound | Medium | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Water engineer transitioned to a full-stack developer after completing the Microverse program. Boasting a varied skill set and experiences, proactive in approach and fluent in several languages such as Javascript, Ruby, and SQL. Proficient in frameworks and technologies like Ruby on Rails and React. Throughout this journey, extensively engaged in pair programming and remote collaboration. Such experiences notably sharpened both technical and non-technical communication abilities, making a premier collaborator for both remote and on-site teams.

## **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev

Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Problem-solving.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

February 2023 - Present

Full Stack Web Developer & Mentor

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 50+ projects both independently and via pair programming.

Meals-API — This project is a basic website that displays meals from an API, displays their instructions, and allow the user to add comment and likes.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, and Javascript). Click here for the live demo.

Property\_rental— It's a web app to add and display scores from a game using an API to POST and GET data.

Built with: (React, Ruby on Rails, CSS, API, Rspec, and Jest). Click here for the repository.

# **MICROVERSE**

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) March 2023 - Present

- Mentored 3 assigned mentees and over 5 other new software development students, providing technical support through code reviews, and debugging.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.
- Helped an external junior software developer by providing assistance for 2 freelance projects and improved website accessibility and performance.

## **SONEB**

Cotonou, Benin

Senior Technician

February 2018 - September 2022

- Assured both the conception (drawing, modelling) and the realization of 1000+ water supply
- Temporarily acted as the head of the distribution department for 2 months during his holidays.
- Conducted the entire feasibility studies for over 500 projects related to potable water supply and the relocation of potable water networks, and have supervised the implementation of more than 100 of them.
- Developed one Excel program for hydraulic calculations and simulations.

## **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE February 2023 - Present

## Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

University of Abomey-Calavi

Bachelor in Hydrology and Water Resources Management October 2013 – September 2016

 Studied Hydrology, modelling, CAD, data management, and statistics with R programming language.